Mustafa Akbari Software Engineer

Email: Akbarimustafa64@gmail.com

Phone: 00491795253045 Birth date: 06.12.1991

Address: Am Steinfeld 3, 85659 Forstern, Germany

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mustafa-akbari-289543219/

GitHub: https://github.com/ci-mustafa



Experienced IT professional with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science and over 5 years in IT administration, database management. Proven ability to solve problems and communicate effectively. Currently advancing skills through a Full Stack Development program at Code Institute. Seeking to contribute to and grow within a development team.

Technical Skillset

Technologies	Databases	Frameworks	Containers	APIs	Operating sys	VC sys
Python JavaScript CSS3, HTML5	MySQL Postgres	Django, jQuery Bootstrap, Flask	Docker	Restfull API	Windows Linux	Agile Git Github

Portfolio Projects

- **ApplyWise** ApplyWise is a robust web application designed to streamline the job application process for users. It empowers individuals to take control of their job applications, providing a user-friendly platform with a range of features that enhance the application experience. Technologies Used Python, CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript, Django.
 - GitHub link: https://github.com/ci-mustafa/applywise | Live link: https://applywise-f12ef2315c63.herokuapp.com/
- Expenses Tracker Expenses Tracker is a Python terminal program that allows users to save and view their incomes and expenses. It
 also provides a summary of the remaining balance by calculating the difference between incomes and expenses.
 Technologies Used Python.
 - GitHub link: https://github.com/ci-mustafa/Expenses-Tracker | live link: https://wallet-watcher-ee66c311b54b.herokuapp.com/
- Color Code Challange Color Code Challenge is an online platform designed for programmers and designers who work extensively
 with hex color codes. This platform offers a unique opportunity for users to enhance their understanding of hex color codes through
 consistent practice. Technologies Used Javascript, CSS3, HTML5.
 - GitHub link: https://github.com/ci-mustafa/Color-Code-Challenge | live link: https://ci-mustafa.github.io/Color-Code-Challenge/
- Code Connect This platform is designed to engage individuals passionate about coding and eager to enhance their skills through
 collaborative learning. With intuitive navigation and a user-friendly sign-up form, aspiring coders can apply to join our coding
 community and embark on a journey of growth and discovery. Technologies Used HTML5, CSS3.

GitHub link: https://github.com/ci-mustafa/code-connect | live link: https://ci-mustafa.github.io/code-connect/

Work Experience

March 2017–October 2021

Database Administrator

UHCC, Afg

- Designed and created databases using MySQL, and integrated with third-party applications via MySQL Workbench.
- Maintained database standards and policies, achieving 99.9% uptime.
- Managed database availability and performance.
- Implemented event triggers for problem detection.
- Performed database maintenance and optimization, improving performance of the database.
- Monitor usage and security.

February 2015–January 2017

IT Administrator

TMB, Afg

- Troubleshot network issues, reducing downtime by 20%.
- Managed and maintained printers, copiers, and fax machines for 100+ users.
- Conducted server maintenance and implemented disaster recovery plans, achieving 99.9% data availability.
- Monitored UPS workstations and operational printers.
- Provided backup support for workflow systems.
- Ensured password and data security in desktop environments.



Education

February 2024–Present Code Institute Dublin, Ireland (Remote)

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development(Credit Rated by University of West of Scotland)

May 2022–October 2023 Skills Enhancement Udemy, Code with Mosh (online resources)

November 2010–December 2014 Bachelor of Computer Science Aria University

Certifications

Bachelor of Computer Science
Code Institute - Fullstack Web Development – on going
Code with Mosh – Complate Django (16 hours)
Udemy – 100 Days of Code (54 hours)
Python Programming Masterclass (63 hours)

Language Skills

Good German Fluent English Fluent Turkish Native Persion